<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../fgdc_classic.xsl" ?><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>NYS Office of Information Technology Services, GIS Program Office</origin><pubdate>20141103</pubdate><title>Erie and Niagara Counties Ortho 4 bd 12in</title><geoform>raster digital data</geoform><serinfo><sername>NYS Digital Ortho-imagery Program (NYSDOP)</sername><issue>2014 imagery in Erie and Niagara Counties</issue></serinfo><pubinfo><pubplace>Albany, New York</pubplace><publish>NYS Office of Information Technology Services, GIS Program Office</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>These files contain 2014 digital Ortho-imagery of Erie and Niagara
Counties, New York. Image pixel size is 1' GSD. Image type is 4-band,
RGB &amp; NIR. Image horizontal accuracy is within 4' at the 95%
confidence level (NSSDA). Each file contains an image covering 2000
ft. by 3000 ft. on the ground.</abstract><purpose>This digital Ortho-imagery can serve a variety of purposes, from
general planning to field reference for spatial analysis to a tool
for revision of vector maps. It can also serve as a reference layer
for GIS.</purpose></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20140419</caldate><caldate>20140420</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>ground condition</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>Irregular</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-79.138538</westbc><eastbc>-78.454000</eastbc><northbc>43.379848</northbc><southbc>42.432551</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>none</themekt><themekey>Digital Ortho-imagery</themekey></theme><place><placekt>none</placekt><placekey>Erie and Niagara Counties</placekey><placekey>New York</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>Some imagery tiles are classified as sensitive due to their content.</accconst><useconst>Use of sensitive imagery, if granted, is only for the use specified in the request.</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Tim Ruhren</cntper><cntorg>NYS ITS GIS Program Office</cntorg></cntperp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>State Office Campus Building 7A, 4th Floor, 1220 Washington Avenue</address><city>Albany</city><state>New York</state><postal>12242</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>518-242-5029</cntvoice><cntfax>518-322-4976</cntfax><cntemail>tim.ruhren@its.ny.gov</cntemail><hours>9am -4:30pm Easten time</hours></cntinfo></ptcontac><datacred>NYS ITS GIS Progam Office</datacred><secinfo></secinfo><native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 10.2</native></idinfo><dataqual><logic>The dataset contains raster images or digital ortho images so the
logical consistency report is not applicable. The file naming
convention was supplied by New York State. When the ortho tiles were
created the file names were restricted to a numeric value representing
the lower left corner of the ortho tile. These tiles were then all
renamed using a batch script so that they reflected the N.Y. state
standard (i.e. "c_10470162_12_09600_4bd_2009.tif"). Consistency of
file naming was ensured by using a batch process. The file naming
convention consists of the first letter for Central, East, West or
Long Island for New York State Plane Coordinate Systems (NYSPCS). The
following four numeric characters represent the first four characters
of the "X" coordinate value for the tile's lower left corner
coordinate in NYSPCS and the next four characters represent the first
four characters of the "Y" coordinate value for the tile's lower left
corner coordinate in NYSPCS. The next two numeric characters represent
the tile's Ground Sampling Distance (GSD) value in ft. The following
five numeric characters represent the Above Mean Terrain (AMT) nominal
height at which the DMC sensor recorded or collected the original
imagery for the corresponding area. The next three characters are
"4bd" for 4-band ortho-photos. Lastly, the last four numeric digits
represent the year in which the particular ortho was created.</logic><complete>The project consisted of 7838 final tiles.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>+/-4 ft. at the 95% confidence level (NSSDA) for 12 inch resolution.</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdesc>This dataset contains orthoimagery as part of the contract to
provide new natural color digital aerial imagery with airborne
GPS-IMU control and ground surveyed control to develop and support
4 band (RGBIR) 8 bit 12 inch pixel resolution of the West region
of New York, including Erie and Niagara Counties. An North-South
flight line orientation was planned and flown for Erie and Niagara
Counties. The area was planned and flown with Keystone's Aerial
Survey's Ultracam Eagle digital mapping camera UCE-00817310
equipped with flight navigation systems and airborne GPS and
inertial measurement units flown at an approximate altitude of
15108' above mean ground elevation. An average image footprint of
20010' x 13080' size image was captured. A total of 20 flight
lines and 1015 exposures were captured for the West region.
Imagery was captured between April 19th and April 20th, 2014, with
a sun angle exceeding 30 degrees. Images were broken into blocks,
which were divided into sub-blocks for aerial triangulation (AT)
processing. Automatic Point Measurement (APM) was run on the
images to measure terrain points to tie the images together. The
imagery was then used in the AT process in Socet Set/Orima where
tie point measurement was performed and independent ground control
points and airborne GPS were introduced to further refine the
data. The DTM data was then applied in the orthorectification
process to produce 4-band RGB-IR digital orthoimages free of
distortion. All ortho rectified images were reviewed for
consistency with project requirements before the mosaicking and
tiling process. Bridge distortions and other errors were corrected
at this stage. As part of the mosaicking and tiling process in
OrthoVista, all images were adjusted for color and radiometric
differences over large blocks. The individual tiles produced were
then inspected in a final QA/QC process for overall image quality
with all undesirable artifacts and errors corrected before
delivery. The end product for the South region was 7838 seamless
8-bit 4-band RGB-IR image tiles, 2000 by 3000 feet wide in
TIFF/TFW format. Imagery was also delivered in JP2/J2W format at a
10:1 compression ratio.</procdesc><procdate>201409</procdate><srcprod>Aerial Imagery</srcprod><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Brian Tolley</cntper><cntorg>Axis Geospatial, LLC</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>Production Manager</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>101 Bay St</address><city>Easton</city><state>Maryland</state><postal>21601</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>410-822-1441</cntvoice><cntemail>btolley@axisgeospatial.com</cntemail><hours>9am - 5pm Eastern Time</hours></cntinfo></proccont></procstep></lineage><cloud>&lt;1%</cloud></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Raster</direct><rastinfo></rastinfo></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><mapproj><mapprojn>Transverse Mercator</mapprojn><transmer><sfctrmer>0.999375</sfctrmer><longcm>-76.583333333333333333</longcm><latprjo>40.0</latprjo><feast>249999.9998983998</feast><fnorth>0.000000</fnorth></transmer></mapproj><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.000000</absres><ordres>0.000000</ordres></coordrep><plandu>survey feet</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>D_North_American_1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo></eainfo><distinfo><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><transize>0.004</transize></digtinfo></digform></stdorder></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20141103</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Tim Ruhren</cntper><cntorg>NYS ITS GIS Program Office</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>NYS GIS Clearinghouse</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>State Office Campus Building 7A, 4th Floor, 1220 Washington Avenue</address><city>Albany</city><state>New York</state><postal>12242</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>518-242-5029</cntvoice><cntfax>518-322-4976</cntfax><cntemail>tim.ruhren@its.ny.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc></metainfo></metadata>